<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>An answer to a printed paper, entituled The case of Mary Dutchess of Norfolk</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1700</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 4 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 1 1-bit group-IV TIFF page image.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2013-12">2013-12 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B08376</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing A3339A</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R172337</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">64550875</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 64550875</idno>
            <idno type="VID">184329</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B08376)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 184329)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English Books, 1641-1700 ; 2858:7)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>An answer to a printed paper, entituled The case of Mary Dutchess of Norfolk</title>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([1] p.).   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>s.n.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1700]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Caption title.</note>
                  <note>Place and date of publication suggested by Wing (2nd ed.).</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in: Cambridge University Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Norfolk, Mary Howard, --  Duchess of, 1659?-1705 --  Trials, litigation, etc.</term>
               <term>Norfolk, Henry Howard, --  Duke of, 1655-1701 --  Trials, litigation, etc.</term>
               <term>Trials (Divorce) --  England --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Divorce --  England --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Broadsides --  England --  17th century.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2012-05</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-06</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-08</date>
            <label>John Pas</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-08</date>
            <label>John Pas</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-02</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:184329:1"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:184329:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <head>AN ANSWER To a Printed Paper, Entituled THE CASE of <hi>Mary</hi> Dutcheſs of <hi>Norfolk.</hi>
            </head>
            <p>IF notorious Untruths and falſe Inferences deſerve the Name of a ſcandalous Libel, the ſaid Printed Caſe is one.</p>
            <p>The Caſe ſets forth, That her Father, the late Earl of <hi>Peterborough,</hi> paid 10000 <hi>l.</hi> in Money, and ſettled near 1000 <hi>l. per Ann.</hi> in Lands, the remainder thereof to the Duke and his Heirs; and a Perſonal Eſtate of 10000 <hi>l</hi> (after the Deceaſe of the ſaid Earl and Counteſs) and alſo 1000 <hi>l. per Ann.</hi> for twenty Years: Beſides very rich Jewels, Plate, and other things of great value, which the ſaid Dutcheſs brought into the Duke's Fa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mily. And it's pretended, that her Grace hath, ſince her Separation, paid great Debts that had been contracted for the ſupport of the Duke's Honour and his Service.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Anſwer.</hi> Neither the Duke, nor his Father, received from his Grace's Family any more than 1000 <hi>l.</hi> to evidence which, if the Duke pays back the 10000 <hi>l.</hi> as the Bill directs, then her Eſtate is as entire and free to all intents, as if he had never married her.</p>
            <p>As to his having 1000 <hi>l. per Ann.</hi> for twenty Years to his Uſe, as is pretended, the Duke abſolutely denys it; or that he has Jewels, Plate, or any thing of Five Pounds value from her or her Family: But ſoon after they married, he was obliged to bor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>row 1500 <hi>l.</hi> to buy Linnen and Houſhold Goods.</p>
            <p>That within three Years, which happened between the late Duke's Death, and the parting of the now Duke and Dutcheſs, ſhe ran him out by extravagant expenſes, near 30000 <hi>l.</hi> above his Income; to pay which obliged him to ſell his Life in 2400 <hi>l. per Ann.</hi> out of his Eſtate in <hi>Suſſex</hi> and <hi>Yorkſhire.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>That ſhe has been ſo far from paying any debts for his Honour and Service, that he has been ſued, and forced to pay ſeveral conſiderable Sums to Trades-men (contract<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed by her without his Privacy) tho' ſhe had a 1000 <hi>l.</hi> a Year Pin-money all the while.</p>
            <p>That upon her refuſal to go into the Country, and her Fathers refuſing to receive her in any Houſe of his, ſhe at her own requeſt choſe to go into <hi>France.</hi> But the Duke did not concern himſelf whether ſhe came back, or not, nor ever heard of her change of Religion, till he felt it (as well as heard it) by her ſueing him before the then High Commiſſioned Court for Alimony, which forced him to retire beyond Sea, from whence he returned about two Months before the King's Landing.</p>
            <p>It is a great aſſurance that the Dutcheſs's Agents have, to mention what was Sworn by her Servants, as diſproving <hi>Hauſeur</hi> and <hi>Vaneſs,</hi> when it appeared ſo plainly that they were taught a Leſſon which they greatly miſtook, and inſtead of diſproving, con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>firmed thechief part of the others Evidence.</p>
            <p>And its pleaſant, that inſtead of <hi>Suſannah Barrington,</hi> who has been charged with the Privacy of the whole intrigue, and appears to have been in the Dutcheſs's Service all along, and likewiſe ſince the bringing in this Bill, they ſhould advance that Infamous Witneſs <hi>Frances Knight</hi> to be the Dutcheſs's Woman.</p>
            <p>What they ſay of <hi>Bayly</hi>'s contradicting <hi>Hauſeur,</hi> is upon a miſtake, which <hi>Bayly</hi> him<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelf ſoon Corrected: And the Dutcheſs's Servants were ſo far from proving the <hi>Dutch</hi>-Woman <hi>Vaneſs</hi> turned away before the rejecting the laſt Bill; that one of the Dutcheſs's Witneſſes proves her to have been the Dutcheſs's Servant while that Bill was de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pending.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
